Guide to the Tamiment Library Web Collection on Labor Unions and Organizations WEB.ARC.002
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Tamiment Library Web Collection on Labor Unions and Organizations
2007-ongoing
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Tamiment Library
WEB.ARC.002
101 websites
The Tamiment Library Web Collection on Labor Unions, first began by Tamiment in 2007, contains webpages of national and regional labor unions, as well as departments and divisions of trade unions. Most of the websites captured are either national American unions or New York metropolitan area local unions. Unions represent workers from many different industries, including the service industry, construction, communication workers, transport workers, manufacturing, government, and entertainment industry. Websites contain information on bargaining and agreements, organizing, member benefits, history, legislative activities, event and conference information, news and blog posts, and other union information.
Historical/Biographical Note
Tamiment Library, New York University began web archiving in 2007 as part of a grant given by the National Digital Information Infrastructure and Preservation Program (NDIPP) of the Library of Congress. As most unions, left movements, progressive organizations, and others stop creating ephemeral material and paper based collections and move most of their administrative and informational material to the web, Tamiment continued to document the changing face of the labor and left movement into the web era. Tamiment uses the California Digital Library's Web Archiving Service (WAS) as their tool to capture and preserve websites. WAS was created in 2007 and Tamiment is one of its earliest partners. The California Digital Library provides the storage and infrastructure for the project.
Related Archival Material
Tamiment Library Web Collection on Organizations
Tamiment Library Web Collection on Individuals
Guide to the Printed Ephemera Collection on Trade Unions (PE 001)
Access Restrictions
Archived websites are open to researchers without restrictions. Archived websites are made publically available 6 months after the initial capture.
Take Down Policy
Tamiment respects robot txt exclusions and requests from websites with robot txt exclusions to allow our crawler to capture their website. Tamiment will also honor the website owner's request to remove their website from the collection. To request a site removal, please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu
Scope and Content Note
The Tamiment Library Web Collection on Labor Unions and Organizations, first began by Tamiment in 2007, contains webpages of national and regional labor unions, as well as departments and divisions of trade unions. This is an assembled collection, the websites were selected by the archivists. Most of the websites captured are either national American unions or New York metropolitan area local unions. Unions collected in this finding aid represent workers from many different industries, including the service industry, construction, communication workers, transport workers, manufacturing, government, and entertainment industries.
Union websites contain information on their committees, their constitution and by-laws, board members, publications, organizing and mobilization materials, conference materials, member benefits and services, legislative reports and other political action committee materials, information on districts and locals, event listings, and blogs. The websites act to inform their members of their benefits and rights, as well as to create support for their initiatives. Many websites contain information related to strikes and other actions taken up by the unions and document the success and failures of the campaigns. Evidence of union collaboration and mergers are also documented in the web archives.
Other websites in this collection are related to labor education and history, cultural groups, labor festivals, labor legislation lobbying groups, labor action websites, labor councils, labor news websites, job listings, and union products. Many of these organizations are not traditionally unions, but provide support and help to organize workers for better pay, benefits, and representation in the workplace. The collection also aims to document the efforts to organize low-wage service sector workers and minority, immigrant, and female workers.
These websites contain a huge variety of media, which include videos, pdfs, blog postings (including Tumblr and Wordpress blogs), petitions, news feeds, audio, message boards, and other media. These websites often act to document and update upon the organizations' activities, schedule upcoming events, build awareness of their cause or organization, information on projects the organizations are working on, and writings and articles by members of the organization.
The web collection documents the publicly available content of the web page, it does not archive material that is password protected or blocked due to robot txt exclusions. Although Tamiment attempts to archive the entirety of a website, certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. This can include videos (Youtube, Vimeo, or otherwise), pdfs (including Scribd or another pdf reader), rss feeds/plug-ins (including twitter), commenting platforms (disqus, facebook), presi, images, or anything that is not native to the site.
Arrangement
Websites are arranged alphabetically.
Existence and Location of Originals
Clicking on the links provided in the container list will take the user to the Web Archiving Service (WAS) page for the website. Sometimes the original website is still available on the live web and the original URL may be available. To get to the original web page, click the live link provided in the "Latest Starting URL" field on the WAS page.
Accruals
In general, new crawls of sites are added quarterly. New sites are added to finding aids upon completion of 6 month embargo.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. This can include videos (including Youtube and Vimeo), pdfs (including Scribd or another pdf reader), rss feeds/plug-ins (including Twitter), commenting platforms (disqus, Facebook), presi, images, or anything that is not native to the site. Other parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes Javascript, streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Robot txt exclusions also change the formatting of websites from their original display, websites with robot txt exclusions often display as an index.
Keyword and file-type search are also available to archived websites through the Web Archiving Service (WAS). To search for keywords within archived websites, click a site name link in the container list. From that page, click the "search" tab on the top left corner. From the search page, you can search by keyword, URL, and file type across all captures of one site or all the sites in the project.
Custodial History
The archived websites were migrated from the California Digital Library's Web Archiving Service to the Internet Archive's Archive-It Service in November 2015. The links to California Digital Library were removed in October 2017.
Labor unions -- United States -- History; Labor movement -- Political activity -- United States.; Labor movement -- United States.; Labor -- United States.; Labor unions -- United States.
- 1199SEIU United Healthcare Workers East Archived Website, Jun 18, 2010 - ongoing
  Scope and Contents note
  United Healthcare Workers East (1199SEIU), founded in 1932 as the Local 1199, is a local union of the Service Employees International Union, representing more than 300,000 members. Members work in homecare, hospital and nursing home industries, as well as pharmacies, freestanding clinics, and other healthcare settings. The mission of the union is to improve and expand quality patient care, to protect and improve the lives of members and their families, and to work in solidarity with working people in SEIU's communities and around the world. In 1998, they affiliated to the Service Employees International Union (SEIU). Since 1998, 15 healthcare local unions throughout New York State, New Jersey, the District of Columbia, Florida, Maryland and Massachusetts have merged with 1199SEIU.
  Home health aides |x Labor unions |z United States.; Medical personnel |x Labor unions |z Northeastern States.; Hospitals |x Employees |x Labor unions |z United States.
- 32BJ Service Employees International Union Archived Website, Apr 5, 2013 - ongoing; Service Employees International Union. Local 32B-32J (New York, N.Y.)
  Service Employees International Union (SEIU), 32BJ is a New York based property service workers union, made up of approximately 120,000 workers (as of this writing in 2013). It was founded in 1921 as the Building Service Employees International Union. In 1968 the union was renamed the Service Employees International Union and in 1977, the Local 32B union had merged with Local 32J. Today, the union's members consists of primarily janitors, property maintenance workers, doormen, security officers, window cleaners, building engineers, and school and food service workers. The website contains a blog, information on the activities of their political action committee, contracts, and campaigns.
  Service industries workers -- Labor unions -- United States.; Service industries workers -- New York (State)
- Actors' Equity Association Archived Website, Sep 23, 2007 - ongoing; Actors' Equity Association
  Actors' Equity Association ("AEA" or "Equity"), founded in 1913, is the labor union that represents more than 48,000 actors and stage managers in the United States. Equity seeks to advance, promote and foster the art of live theatre as an essential component of our society. Equity negotiates wages and working conditions and provides a wide range of benefits, including health and pension plans, for its members. Actors' Equity is a member of the AFL-CIO, and is affiliated with FIA, an international organization of performing arts unions. The website contains their newsletter, Equity News, news listings, member benefits, agreements, election information, and meeting listings.
  Actors -- Labor unions -- United States.; Stage managers |x Labor unions |z United States.
- Actors' Fund of America Archived Website, Mar 29, 2009 - ongoing; Actors' Fund of America
  The Actors Fund, a nonprofit human services organization founded in 1882, serves professionals in film, theater, television, music, opera, and dance through programs that address their professional needs. The Fund serves more than 12,000 performing arts and entertainment professionals across the country every year, and reaches hundreds of thousand through the Fund's online resources. The Fund operates as a safety net, to provide programs and services, including comprehensive social services, health services, supportive and affordable housing, employment and training services, and skilled nursing and assisted living care for performing arts and entertainment professionals in need. The website contains information on their services and programs, tickets to upcoming performances and events, and education and workshops.
  Fraternal organizations |z United States.
- ACT-UAW (UAW Local 7902) Archived Website, Nov 21, 2014-ongoing
  Scope and Content Note
  ACT-UAW Local 7902 (Adjuncts Coming Together) represents over 4,000 part- time and adjunct teachers at the New School and New York University. The union was formed in 2002 by adjuncts at NYU, which first ratified their first contract in 2004. In 2004, adjuncts at the New School began to negotiate, and reached an agreement with the New School in 2005. The union has successfully negotiated better pay, job security, partially subsidized health care, pension benefits, and promoted transparency within the universities' budgetary systems. The website contains their current contracts, information about their committees and stewards, election results, their newsletter, Adjunct Voice, and a gallery of their members' art.
  College teachers' unions -- New York (State) -- New York; New School (New York, N.Y.); New York University
- AFL-CIO New York City Central Labor Council Archived Website, Mar 9, 2010 - ongoing
  The New York City Central Labor Council (NYCCLC) is a non-profit labor membership organization devoted to supporting, advancing and advocating for the working people of New York City. The NYCCLC brings together 300 local unions from every trade, occupation, public and private sector of the New York economy. The Council represents 1.3 million workers, including teachers, truck drivers, operating engineers, nurses, construction workers, electricians, firefighters, retail workers, janitors, train operators, bakers, and others. NYCCLC is affiliated with the AFL-CIO. The website includes information on the issues that they work on, including healthcare, retirement, employment, education, civil rights, and immigration. The website also contains news and event listings.
  Central labor councils.
- Albert Shanker Institute Archived Website, Jul 26, 2009 - ongoing
  The Albert Shanker Institute is a nonprofit foundation dedicated to advancing democratic ideals, improving the quality of public education, and conducting research in the labor movement and the sociology of work. The foundation sponsors research, holds roundtable discussions, and publishes various reports. The Institute was named for Albert Shanker (1928-1997), the late president of the American Federation of Teachers.
  Democracy -- United States.; Education -- United States.; Labor unions -- United States.
- Amalgamated Transit Union (ATU) Archived Website, Dec 11, 2009 - ongoing
  The Amalgamated Transit Union (ATU) is the largest labor organization representing transit workers in the United States and Canada. Founded in 1892, the ATU today is comprised of over 190,000 members in 264 local unions spread across 44 states and nine provinces. Composed of metropolitan, interstate, and school bus drivers; paratransit, light rail, subway, streetcar, and ferry boat operators; mechanics and other maintenance workers; clerks, baggage handlers, municipal employees, and others. The ATU works to promote transit issues and fights for the interests of its hard-working members. ATU is a member the AFL-CIO, and the Canadian Labor Congress (CLC).
  Transport workers |x Labor unions |z United States.
- Amalgamated Transit Union, Local 1181 Archived Website, Jan 16, 2013 - ongoing
  Amalgamated Transit Union, Local 1181 is the largest local in the United States for the Amalgamated Transit Union. It represents drivers, escorts, school bus drivers, and mechanics in New York City, Westchester County and Long Island. The website contains information on their school bus strike in 2013, their pension and welfare fund, and a calendar.
  Transport workers |x Labor unions |z New York (State) |z New York |x History.; Transport workers |x Labor unions |z United States.
- Amalgamated Transit Union Local 1555 Archived Website, Oct 22, 2013-ongoing
  The Amalgamated Transit Union (ATU) Local 1555 represents approximately 900 front-line workers of the Bay Area Rapid Transit (BART) system in California. The websites contains information on the 2013 BART strike.
  Strikes and lockouts -- United States.; Transport workers |x Labor unions |z United States.
- American Federation of Government Employees (AFGE) Archived Website, Dec 8, 2009 - ongoing
  The American Federation of Government Employees (AFGE), founded in 1932, is an American labor union representing over 600,000 employees of the federal government, about 5,000 employees of the District of Columbia, and a few hundred private sector employees, mostly in and around federal facilities. Workers in many functions of government at every federal agency depend upon AFGE for legal representation, legislative advocacy, technical expertise and informational services. It is affiliated with the AFL-CIO.
  Collective bargaining |x Government employees |z United States.
- American Federation of Musicans, Local 802 Archived Website, Jan 28, 2009-ongoing; American Federation of Musicians. Local 802
  Local 802 of the American Federation of Musicians is a local union of professional musicians living or working in New York City, Nassau and Suffolk counties, New York. The union's mission is to fight for the interests and well being of the musicians employed in New York's music and entertainment industries through organizing and collective bargaining as well as through legislative and political action. The website contains agreements and contracts, their Allegro magazine and other news postings, and event listings.
  Musicians |x Labor unions |z New York (State) |z New York.
- American Federation of Musicians of the United States and Canada (AFM) Archived Website, Dec 4, 2009 - ongoing
  The American Federation of Musicians of the United States and Canada (AFM) is a labor union of professional musicians in the United States and Canada, founded in 1896. The AFM represents the interests of professional musicians by negotiating fair agreements, protecting ownership of recorded music, securing benefits such as health care and pension, and lobbying legislators.
  Musicians -- Labor unions -- Canada.; Musicians -- Labor unions -- United States.
- American Federation of State, County, and Municipal Employees (AFSCME), District Council 1707 Archived Website, Nov 28, 2012 - ongoing; AFSCME. District Council 1707
  District Council 1707 of the American Federation of State, County and Municipal Employees (AFSCME) is the only council within AFSCME that is chartered exclusively to represent private, nonprofit employees. It currently represents about 25,000 workers throughout the New York City area (and New York State), including those within private sector fundraising and advocacy agencies, case work and group work agencies, teaching and related organizations, child care centers, home care services, and Head Start programs. The website contains information on the political action committee, class and workshops, benefits, and news.
  Municipal officials and employees |x Labor unions |z United States.
- American Federation of State, County and Municipal Employees (AFSCME) District Council 37 (New York, N.Y.) Archived Website, Sep 24, 2007 - ongoing; AFSCME. District Council 37 (New York, N.Y.)
  District Council 37 (DC 37) is a local union of the American Federation of State, County, and Municipal Employees (AFSCME) which represents New York City public employees and employees in the healthcare industry. DC 37 was founded in 1944.
  Municipal officials and employees |x Labor unions |z New York (State) |z New York.
- American Federation of State, County, and Municipal Employees (AFSCME), District Council 37, Local 1930, New York Public Library Guild Archived Website, Jan 28, 2009 - ongoing; AFSCME. Local 1930 (New York, N.Y.)
  The New York Public Library Guild Local 1930, formed in 1968, represents almost 2,000 clericals, library technical assistants, information assistants, librarians, and other titles. Members of Local 1930 are employed by the New York Public Library, by the City of New York in its branch libraries, and the libraries of mayoral departments and agencies. The bargaining unit includes professional, non-professional and technical positions. As an activist union, they believe libraries are the backbone of democracy and unions are the vehicles to defend the economic rights of clerks, library technical assistants, information assistants, librarians, and others.
  Librarians |z New York (State) |z New York.; Library employees |x Labor unions |z New York (State) |z New York.
- American Federation of State, County, and Municipal Employees (AFSCME), District Council 37, Local 983 Archived Website, Mar 28, 2014-ongoing
  AFSCME (American Federation of State, County and Municipal Employees), Local 983 is one of the District Council 37's earliest locals, founded in the 1950s. The union initially represented motor vehicle operators, but came to include different blue collar employees, including high pressure plant tenders, parks workers, asbestos handlers, assistant city highway repairers, city seasonal aides and other municipal and public employee jobs. 1998-2013, Mark Rosenthal was elected president of Local 983. In 2013, Joe Puleo was elected president of the local. The website contains information on the union's benefits, contracts, and event listings.
  Motor vehicle drivers |z United States.
- American Federation of Teachers (AFT) Archived Website, Jun 18, 2011 - ongoing
  The American Federation of Teachers (AFT), founded in 1916, represents the economic, social and professional interests of classroom teachers. It is an affiliated international union of the AFL-CIO. The AFT has more than 3,000 local affiliates nationwide, 43 state affiliates, and more than 1.5 million members. Five divisions within the organization represent the broad spectrum of AFT's membership: teachers; paraprofessionals and school-related personnel (PSRP); local, state and federal employees; higher education faculty and staff; and nurses and other healthcare professionals. In addition, the union includes more than 170,000 retiree members.
  Teachers' unions -- United States.
- American Federation of Television and Radio Artists (AFTRA) Archived Website, Jan 29, 2009 - Jul 11, 2012; American Federation of Television and Radio Artists
  The American Federation of Television and Radio Artists (AFTRA), founded in 1937, is a national labor union representing performers, journalists and other artists working in the entertainment and news media. AFTRA's scope of representation covers broadcast, public and cable television, radio, sound recordings, "non-broadcast" and industrial material, as well as Internet and digital programming. AFTRA advocates on legislative and public policy issues that directly affect members' wages and working conditions. This includes lobbying and support for such issues as ownership consolidation in the broadcast industry, Equal Employment Opportunity laws and regulations, copyright and performance rights issues, "non-compete" restrictions, OSHA and local safety regulations, and more. AFTRA also represents artists and journalists in judicial proceedings, often as amicus, and before the U.S. Copyright Office. In 2012, AFTRA merged with the Screen Actors Guild (SAG) to form SAGAFTRA.
  Television broadcasting -- Employees -- Labor unions -- United States; Radio broadcasting |x Employees |x Labor unions |z United States.
- American Guild of Musical Artists (AGMA) Archived Website, Apr 28, 2009 - ongoing; American Guild of Musical Artists
  The American Guild of Musical Artists, AFL-CIO (AGMA), founded in 1936, is an American labor union that represents 8,000 current and retired opera singers, ballet and other dancers, opera directors, backstage production personnel at opera and dance companies, and figure skaters. AGMA is a branch of Associated Actors and Artistes of America. The website contains auditions listings, agreements and contracts, news and event listings, and information on meetings and board members.
  Performing artists |x labor unions |z United States.
- American Guild of Variety Artists (AGVA) Archived Website, Apr 23, 2012 - ongoing; American Guild of Variety Artists